根据原始天尊圣约记载
And it was written in the Covenant of Primus
“当四十七颗星球连成一线之际
that "when the 47 spheres align
无尽的纷争 终将席卷某个混沌的世间
a perpetual conflict will culminate upon a world forged from chaos
弱者随之消亡 黑暗势力崛起并笼罩四方”
and the weak shall perish in the shadow of a rising darkness."
天上还会下火球吗？
No, sky is raining fire?
不用多说
Goes without say
这的确是个可怕的末世论
it is a doom prophecy after all.
要我说 这纯粹是无稽之谈
I say it's a load of hooey.
我一直以为 古人所说的是我们的母星
I'd always assume the ancients were referring to our home planet
但既然塞博特恩早在千万年前就陷入黑暗…
but being that Cybertron has been dark for eons...
而且 威震天到来之后 这个星球变得多灾多难…
And considering what has befallen this planet since Megatron's arrival here...
哇…
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
这些神论我们能倒背如流 可从没当回事儿
We've known about these superstitions for ages and never gave them a second thought.
现在干嘛这么疑神疑鬼的？
Why all the ominous rumblings now?
因为预言中提到的星球串联现象 近在眼前
Because the planetary alignment to which the prophecy refers is nearly upon us.
而且看起来它的末端…是地球
And it would seem its end point... is Earth.
呃…巧合得太离谱了 是吧？
Eh... Crazy coincidence, yeah, right?
还有多久？
How long are we talking?
最多不过几天时间
A few days, at most.
这个事实固然令人不安
However unsettling this revelation may be
但我更担心另一些人 他们很可能利用预言图谋不轨
I am more concerned about those who might believe that the prophecy speaks to them alone.
我一心寻找宇宙大帝之血 不是为了苟且偷生
I did not seek out the blood of Unicron to simply keep my spark aflame
而是要统领不死大军 征服所有世界！
but to rule undead armies, and conquer worlds!
要想达成夙愿
And to accomplish that
只靠我体内这一小块碎片 是远远不够的
I require more than this mere sliver which lies within me.
那么…我的黑暗能量在哪儿？！
So... where is my Dark Energon?!
就在星云之间 威震天陛下
Out there, Lord Megatron.
早晚都是您的囊中之物！
Just waiting for you to reach out and pluck it!
但您不必如此勉强自己
But you shouldn't push yourself so hard.
您大病初愈
You've had setbacks.
刚从平衡状态苏醒
You were in stasis.
正因为这样 我才必须抓紧时间！
Precisely why I must make up for lost time!
我眼中的未来…无比清晰！
I can see the future, vividly!
可我必须确保它成为现实
But I must ensure its outcome.
因为我就是那个崛起的黑暗势力
For I am the rising darkness
预言必将由我来印证！
of which the prophecy speaks!
跳过 嗯… 小孩捣鬼 气球而已
Pass, um, kid in costume, balloon
不对 等等
nope, hold
小蜂果然很上镜
the camera sure loves Bee.
有什么办法？
What can you do?
一旦当上超级巨星
When you're a superstar
就成了狗仔队的靶子
You're paparazzi bait.
等一下 那是大黄蜂吗？
Wait. Is that Bumblebee?
这是个揭秘网站
On a conspiracy website.
用户可以发布接触外星人的证据
Where users post evidents of close encounters
不过包在我们身上 救护车
but we have it under control, Ratchet.
我们把小蜂的照片抹掉 换成…\N“我是火星猫 带我去吃饭吧！”
We just scrub and replace Bee with... Mars Cat says, "Take me to your feeder!"
救护车居然笑了？
Ratchet actually laughed?
嗯 擎天柱 想看点有趣的吗？
Um, Optimus, you wanna see something funny?
不想
No.
别往心里去
Don't take it personally.
领袖就是那个样子
Primes are built that way.
从没见过擎天柱笑 哭 或者有失风度
Never seen Optimus laugh, cry or lose his cool.
擎天柱从来不会轻易表露他的情感
While Optimus certainly keeps his emotions in check
但我比你们中任何一个都更熟悉他
I've known him far longer than any of you have.
成为领袖之前 他不是这样的
And he was different before he was made a Prime.
擎天柱没有一直当领袖吗？
Optimus wasn't always a Prime?
在塞博特恩 伟人并不是天生的
On Cybertron one isn't born into greatness
而是靠努力争取来的
rather, one must earn it.
那么 怎么个不同法？
So, different, how?
他以前是派对狂人吗？
We're talking party animal?
不 不 从前的擎天柱更像是…杰克
No, no, Optimus was more like... Jack.
什么？我一点也不像擎…
What? I'm nothing like Op...
擎天柱 还记得我们追踪的那些家伙吗
Prime, Those tech-guys my department's been tracking.
我们原以为是机械党 因为作案手段非常相似
We figured it was MECH on account of the stealth tactics.
可是不久前
Until moments ago when a security feed at the Pennington-Ebbs Particle Collider captured this.
声波
Soundwave.
拉夫可以帮你把声波换成小猫咪
Raf can swap that out for you with a funny cat.
这个“没脸”的虎子 偷走了最先进的相位导体
The Con without a face made off with the cutting-edge phase conductor.
这里有一份清单 列出了目前为止确认被盗的所有物品
Here is a punch list of everything else we've confirmed stolen to date.
等离子喷射器 中子盾 超正方体
Plasma injector, Neutron Shield, Tesseract.
还差一样东西 他们就能建造…
There is only one thing missing if they are intending to build...
霸天虎太空桥2.0版 即将竣工启动
The Decepticon space bridge 2.0 is nearly ready to launch.
我们只差一个…
All we require is...
如声波所说…
what Soundwave said--
充足的动力源
an ample power source.
这东西所在的基地有重兵把守…
This one lies within a highly fortefied location...
不过是区区人类而已
by human standards.
我可以打通一条隧道
I could tunnel in.
预言成真的时刻就快到了！
The time of prophecy is nearly upon us.
没时间去偷鸡摸狗了
We could no longer afford stealth.
擎天柱 虎子们这次真的坐不住了
Prime, the Cons really stepped out at this time.
他们袭击了一个美军实验室
They hit a U.S. military lab
弟兄们会尽力顶住 等待你们到场
Our boys in green will fend them off till your team shows.
福勒探员 我担心 威震天已经到了破釜沉舟的地步
Agent Fowler, I fear that Megatron's desperation may be at its zenith.
你很清楚 我绝不容许任何一名人类惨遭不测
And you know that I cannot condone even a single human casualty.
我是福勒
Fowler here.
疏散所有人员 立即执行
Evacuate all personnel, immediately.
撤退！
Retreat.
威震天陛下 货已到手
Lord Megatron, package secured
但是汽车人来了
but the Autobots have arrived.
啊！将战舰开往会合地点
Ah! Prepare the warship for rendezvous.
务必当场收货
The package will be ready for pick-up.
大黄蜂 他们可能需要支援
Bumblebee, the team may require back-up.
距离你当前位置三分钟路程 就在高速路上
They are three kliks north from your current position just on the high way.
你可以在出口让拉夫下车
If you drop Raf at the exit ramp
我从那儿把他传送回基地
I can bridge him back to base from there.
没关系 小蜂
It's OK, Bee.
我们可以改天再赛车
We'll go racing another time.
哎呀呀
Well, well.
一个愚蠢的侦察兵掉队了
A foolish scout is stray from the ranks.
擎天柱
Optimus.
威震天
Megatron.
你知不知道 强行把预言变为现实 是种愚蠢的行为？
Do you not see the folly in trying to force a prophecy to fruition?
干嘛要听天由命呢
Why leave matters to fate
我的命运我做主 难道不好吗？
if one can forge one's own destiny?
啊 说到命运…
Ah, speaking of fate...
拉夫！
Raf!
他还在呼吸 但很微弱
He is breathing, barely.
啊哈 看来我不仅拍了一只黄蜂 还捏死一只臭虫
Ah, ha, it would seem I swatted a bee and squashed a bug.
小蜂 别！
Bee, no!
救护车 快把我们传送回去！
Ratchet, bridge us back now!
一定是有汽车人受伤了
We must have an Autobot down.
阿尔茜 照顾好拉斐尔 还有大黄蜂
Arcee, attend to Rafael and Bumblebee.
拉夫？
Raf?
不！
No!
怎么回事？
What happened?
是威震天
Megatron.
快 送进我的实验室
Quickly, into my laboratory.
啊 拉斐尔没有反应
Ah, Rafael isn’t responding.
必须全面检测他的零件 呃…
We must run diagnostics of his assemblage, eh...
生命机能
vital status.
啊 我的工具
Ah, my tools.
全都派不上用场！
They're all wrong!
应该叫我妈来
We need to call my mom.
你妈妈虽然是个护士
Your mother may be a nurse
但她知道能量会对人类身体 造成什么影响吗？
but does she know anything about the effects of energon on the human body?
那你又对人类身体了解多少？
What? Do you know anything about the human body?
妈妈 有急事
Mom it‘s urgent.
弱者会消亡
The weak will perish.
坚强点 拉斐尔
Be strong, Rafael.
动力源即刻准备就绪 威震天陛下
The power source will be ready in no time, Lord Megatron.
我们很快就能到达建造工地了
We’re nearly at the construction site.
还是不够快
Nearly isn' t good enough.
星球即将完成串联
The spheres are aligning.
我不能错过时机 去…
I must not miss my moment to...
威震天陛下？您还好吧？
Lord Megatron? Are you alright?
又来了
Yet again.
我好像能听到宇宙大帝的思想
It is as if I can hear Unicron’s thoughts.
宇宙大帝？那个混沌之神？
Unicron? The Chaos Bringer?
听说 黑暗能量就是他的血液
They say dark energon is his blood.
哈 管他呢
Ha, whatever.
快完成太空桥
Complete the space bridge.
我还有件要事去办
There is something I must attend to.
他是不是看起来…神神叨叨的？
Does he seem to be "losing it"?
有那么一点…
A bit...
妈妈 谢…
Mom, thank...
拿我的包来
Grab my bag.
先检测出他吸收了多少能量 才能决定正确的治疗方案
Measuring the extent of the absorption should determine the proper course of treatment.
如果不赶快稳定这孩子的病情
If I don't get this boy stabilized now
他不可能活着走下手术台
he will not leave this table alive.
你明白吗？
Do you understand me?
呃…
Ah...
小蜂 听着
Bee, listen.
你以为我愿意眼睁睁看着搭档…
You think I don’t know how it feels to watch a partner...
受伤吗？
harmed?
眼下 复仇是帮不了拉夫的
Revenge won't help Raf right now.
你得控制你的情绪
You need to keep your emotions in check.
救护车 拉斐尔怎么样了？
Ratchet, how is Rafael?
现在还不能断言
It is too soon to know.
你的医术高明
He's in good hands.
不是我 擎天柱
Not mine. Optimus
塞博特恩式的傲气让我目中无人
curse my cybertronian pride.
我们已经接纳人类走进我们的生活
We've accepted these human into our lives
但我却对他们的科学和医术…不屑一顾
yet I've bothered to learn so little about their science or medicine.
振作起来 老朋友
Pull yourself together, old friend
拉斐尔需要你
Rafael needs you.
我也变得越来越离不开他了
And I have grown to need him.
锁定我的坐标 启动环陆桥
Lock on to my coordinates and activate the ground bridge.
准备好了
Ready.
隔板 返回基地
Bulkhead, return to base.
我还有事情要做
There is something I must do.
呃 真的吗？
Eh, serious?
长久以来我过于一厢情愿 没有意识到 历史总在不断地重演…
I have been foolish not to see what history has proven over and over again...
汽车人和霸天虎永远不可能志同道合
that Autobots and Decepticons will never mend their ways.
如果没法通过协商解决这场 旷日持久的冲突
If there can be no diplomatic solution to this perpetual conflict
那么我不能再容忍黑暗势力摧毁这里
then I must not allow more darkness to fall upon this
以及任何一个星球
or any planet.
必须消灭威震天！
Megatron must be destroyed!
我只是来讨伐威震天一个人的
I have come for Megatron and him alone.
想活命的 就给我让开！
Stand down and be spared.
我见过这座喷火的高山！
The flaming mountain in my visions.
应该是它在召唤着我…指引着我！
As if it summoned me here... Guided me!
我的太空桥就该建在这里
This is where I am to position my space bridge.
从这个地方
The place from whence
我可以尽情地收集黑暗能量！
I am to harvest dark energon.
威震天 是我 我在你的船上
Megatron, I am here, on your ship.
来和我做个了断吧！
Come and face me!
在这个地方 我即将击败…
The place in which I am to defeat...
最后一位领袖！
the last of the Primes.
听着
Hear this
有哪个霸天虎胆敢动擎天柱一根汗毛
any Decepticon who lays a hand on Optimus Prime
我都要亲自处决他！
will answer to me.
声波 锁定我的坐标
Soundwave, lock onto my coordinates
送我的老对手来接受他的命运吧！
and lead my opponent to his destiny.
杰克 帮我抬拉夫上车
Jack, help me get Raf to the car
必须送他去急救室
he's going to the emergency room.
达比护士
Nurse Darby
人类医生不会明白 折磨他的是什么东西
your doctors won't be able to comprehend what's afflicting him--
他们至少要研究十几年
not without a decade of study.
我没时间吵架
I don't have time to argue.
能量炮的威力足以让一名汽车人当场身亡
The effects of an energon blast on an Autobot can be devastating enough.
更何况他是人类
But this is a human.
没有能量读数
I'm not getting any readings.
我怎么没想到呢？
How could I not have seen this?
感染拉斐尔的应该是黑暗能量才对
Rafael's been infected with dark energon.
威震天 今天你必须服法 向塞博特恩和人类低头认罪
Megatron, today you answer for your crimes against Cybertron and against humanity.
只有一个能活命
One shall stand.
另一个必须死
And one shall fall.
就是你 擎天柱！
You, Optimus Prime!
既然黑暗能量正在侵蚀拉夫体内的器官
If dark energon is devouring Raf from the inside out
我们必须清除它 要尽快
we must expel it, and fast
我知道唯一的可行办法
the only possible way I know.
我需要能量！
I need energon.
等一下 你说过 能量对人体是致命的
Wait. You said energon was devastating to humans.
在一般情况下的确会造成伤害
Under normal circumstances, quite.
不过我要利用入侵拉斐尔身体的黑暗能量 来中和损伤
But I'm relying upon the dark matter currently invading Rafael's body to meet it head on.
先人早已经预见到 你会在此败北
Your defeat here was foreseen by the ancients.
他们说什么来着？
What was it they wrote?
“弱者随之消亡”？
"The weak shall perish"?
尽信书 不如无书
Do not believe everything you read.
把他推过来 快！
I need him over here, now!
脉搏稳定下来了
Pulse rate is stabilizing.
小蜂
Bee.
擎天柱 我们成功了
Optimus, we did it.
我的命运…
My destiny...
不该就这么草草收场！
This isn't how it's supposed to end.
恰恰相反 威震天…
On the contrary, Megatron...
我不允许有其他的结局
I could not have allowed this to end otherwise.
隔板 你让擎天柱一个人去对付威震天？
Bulkhead, you let Optimus face Megatron alone?
我没别的选择
I didn't have a choice.
这可能是陷阱
It could be a trap.
我们得找到他的位置
We need to get a fix on his location.
你刚才的大话是怎么说的 擎天柱？
How was it that you put it, Optimus?
“我不允许有其他的结局”？
"I could not have allowed this to end otherwise?"
我已经锁定了擎天柱的信号
I'm locked on to Optimus' signal.
等一下 这怎么可能？
Wait, how is this possible?
什么？怎么了？
What? What is it?
必须让擎天柱离开那里 快！
We need to get Optimus out of there, now!
哈哈哈…哎呀呀
Haha... Well, well.
看来我苦苦寻找的宇宙大帝之血 不是在星云之间
It seems the blood of Unicron I've been seeking is not out there
而是就在…我的脚下！
but rather, right here!
黑暗能量…居然从地球内部喷发出来？
Dark energon... erupting from the Earth?